Guide to the Jerald Brauer Papers 1925-1999
University of Chicago Library
- Series II: Correspondence, 1940-1970
  - Subseries 5: Correspondence 1964-1966
    - Sl-Sp, Sloyan, Gerard Smith, Barbara Smith, Elwyn Allen Smith, Huston Smucker, Donovan Smylie, John Snodgrass, Ernest Snuggs, R. Grady Soltau, M.E. Sommerfeld, Richard Song, C.S. Sorensen, C.W. Souri, J.D. Sovik, Arne Spaulding, Helen F. Speaks, R. Robert Speel, Charles Spencer, John B. Spiegler, Gerhard Spielmann, Richard Spike, Robert Spinka, Matthew Spitz, Lewis Sponheim, Paul (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - St-Sw, Stahlmann, Jurgen Stassen, Glen Stauffer, John Stazesky, Richard Stauffer, John Steece, Arvel Stein, K. James Sternberger, Dolf Stinnette, Charles Stober, Gertraut Stoeffler, Ernest Stoner, Elizabeth Stone's Motel Storey, William Storr, Richard Stransky, Thomas Streeter, Robert Stucki, Margaret Sturm, Douglas Stutzman, Frances Suelflow, Roy Suenens, Leon-Josef Sullivan, Maxine Swidler, Leonard Switz, Theodore (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - T-V, Tait, L. Gordon Tarbox, Everett Tavard, George Tave, Stuart Tax, Sol Taylor, Charles L. Terrien, Samuel Thomas, Carl Thomas, Virden Thompson, Bard Thompson, G.S. Thompson, J.E. Tillich, Hannah Tisdale, John R. Titus, Harold Tobias, Robert Topmoeller, William Torbet, Robert Trahey, Jane Traub, Janet Trede, Mildred Treffert, John Tucker, William Tucker, Irwin St. John Tucker, William Turner, James Typer, Donald Uecker, Erwin Samuels, Richard University Microfilms Urang, Gunnar Van Dusen, Henry Vatja, Vilmos Varland, John Vikstrom, Richard Vulgamore, Melvin (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - W-Z, Wagner, Matthew Wagoner, Walter Walker, Magdalena Wall, James M. Wallace, Dewey Walther, Christian Wang, Ling-Chi Wang, Leander Ward, Joel Warner, Edward Washington, Joseph Wasson, Margaret Watkins, George Weaver, William Weckman, George Weil, Frank Weinberg, Bernard Weintraub, Helen Weiser, Frederick Weiss, Helmut Weizsacker, Richard Wentz, Frederick Werner, Richard Wessels, Cletus Westlund, Virgil Wettstein, A. Arnold Whipple, George Whitman, Lawrence Whitman, Lauris Wick, Joseph G. Wick, Ruth C. Wienhorst, Sue Wilken, Robert Willebrands, Jan Williams, Daniel Williams, George Williamson, George Winn, Albert Winter, Gibson Winters, Janet Wolf, Herbert Wolfe, Norm Wolf, Richard Word, Dorothy Wright, Dean Zacek, Judith Zampetti, Pier Zatko, James Zeigler, Jesse Zen Buddhist Church Zimdars, Dale (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 6: Correspondence, 1965-1970
    - A-F, Akaishi, Tadashi American Academy of Religion American Association of Theological Schools American Baptist Board of Education and Publication American Jewish Committee Bachmann, E. Theodore Bambury, Ewart Banner, William A. Baptists Beadle, George Bowen, Carroll Busk, Michael Campion, Donald Case, Harold Chapman, Carl Chiacco, Nick Christian Institute for the Study of Religion and Society Clergy and Laymen Concerned about Vietnam Connelly, James Conference of Synod Presidents Cutler, Don Daughjerg, Niels Dalton, James S. Davidson, Glen Van Dusen, Hugh Downs, James C. English, Maurice Donnelley, Gaylord Elkus, Lenore Executive Council of the Episcopal Church Finney, Paul Franklin, John Hope Fund for Theological Education (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - G-M, Grant, Robert M. Green, Lowell Green, Harold J. Hindman, Patricia Hurney, L.W. Jenkins, Daniel Lang, Reuben Leibrecht, Walter Lefebre, Hans Loos, A. William Haas, Harold Endresss, Henry Levi, Edward H. Levich, Marvin Litchfield, Ann McCrossin, Michael McCulloch, Mary W. McDonald, Robert F. Mariners' Temple Mercer, Norman Meredith, Charles P. Miller, Harold Muto, Susan (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - P-Z, Parker, Thom Onheiber, Jerome Pauck, Bill Pinnington, John Pressler, Henry Pyle, Cassie Evans, Randall H. Reitz, Rudiger Robbins, Wallace Scherer, James A. Roth, Erik Schutz, Klaus Seeberger, Hans-Jurgen Seeberger, Elizabeth Sherman, Franklin Shugg, Roger Shuster, George N. Sturm, Phylis A. Tillich, Hannah Thomas, Russell Wallace, Martha Weis, Earl Welch, Claude Wilken, Robert Wittenberg University (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Unassigned Correspondents (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Memos and Minutes (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 7: Correspondence, 1969-1976
    - A, Dupuis, Gerard Abbott, Walter Abe, Masao Academic Policy Committee, University of Chicago Adams, Henry Adams, James Luther Adams, Henry Aden, Ross Art Institute of Chicago, School of Alhstrom, Gosta Akaishi, Tadashi Albert, Harold Alberty, Robert Alderfer, Owen Allen, William Allen, York Almen, Louis Alter, Barbara Altizer, Thomas Athenagoras, The Oecumenical Patriarch American Airlines American Council of Learned Societies A.M./Ph.D. Committee Meeting American Philosophical Society American Society of Church History Anderson, Alan Anderson, Helen Anderson, James Anderson, Paul Andrews, Barbara Anshen, Ruth Nenda Aren, Edward Armstrong, Norman Armstrong, Thomas Asheim, Ivan Atkinson, James Augspurger, Diana Avery, Gary (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - B-Be, Bachmann, E. Theodore Baerwald, Hans H. Bailey's Hotel Bailey, J. Martin Baird, Russell M. Bakken, Norman K. Ball, George Bambury, Ewart Bangs, Carl Banner, William Barlass, Jack Barranger, Milly Barranger, G. Barth, Joseph Bartlett, Gene Bartlow, Robert Barts, Merlin Batey, Richard Beadle, George Beattie, Paul Beaver, R. Pierce Bechtold, Paul I. Beckman, Peter Ball, Harold Bell, Robert Benedict, Donald Bennett, Boyce Bennett, John C. Bennett, J. Lloyd Benson, E.C. Benton, William Benz, Ernst Berchtold, Ted Bergamo Berkhof, H. Bernard, Paul Bernards, Solomon Berry, Brian J.L. Berthhold, Fred (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Bl-Bu, Black Caucus Blackmore, James Blake, Eugene Carson Blakemore, W. Barnett Blanco, Florine Bland, Joan Blenkinsopp, Joseph Von Blomberg, R.F. Blum, Walter Bobilya, Mary Beth Boegehold, A.L. Bollens, Jack Booty, John Borg, Elmer A. Bower, William Clayton Bowman, John Boyd, Thomas Braden, Charles Braley, Bernard Brandt, Hermann Brauer, Robert Braune, Walther Breedlove, Charlene Breen, Quirinus Breward, Ian Brooks, Jerome Brown, Howard Brown, John Pairman Browning, Don Bryant, Sherwood Bugbee, Henry Lewis, Kevin Burhoe, Ralph Burkill, T. Alec Burns, Norman Burtchaell, James T. Busch, Raymond Butler, G. Paul (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - C-Ce, Cabaniss, Alan Cady, Kendall Cain, Seymour Calian, Carnegie Samuel Cameron, Richard Campbell, Roald Campiche, Roland Cannon, William Capps, Donald Carleton, Stephen Carlson, J. Bert Carlson, Leland Carlson, Martin Carman, Newton Carr, Aute Carr, Frank Catholic Seminaries, University of Chicago Divinity School (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Ch-Cu, Chadwick, Henry Cogley, John Chambers, R. Fred Chaney, Charles Chapman, G. Clark Chapman, Joseph I. Charlesworth, James H. Charlesworth, M. J. Charlot, John Ching, Leonard Cholke, Robert Chukka, Joseph Cioran, Emile Claffey, Michael Clark, John Rusking Clebsch, William Cleland, James T. Come, Arnold Clifford, N. Keith Clymer, Wayne Coburn, Robert Cochrane, Eric Cohn, Daniel Cole, William Graham Commissioners, Board of Election Conrad, Loyal Constantino, Leo Lenox-Conyngham, G.P. Cobb, John Cook, William J. Cooke, Gerald Cornell, William Cragg, Gerald Creel, Austin Cogley, John Croskery, Robert Crossan, Dominic Crummey, Clifford Cullmann, Oscar Cushman, Robert (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - D, Dahl, Edward Daly, Charles Neufeld-Recommendation Darge, Ronald David, P. Davidson, Arthur Davidson, Glen Davies, W.D. Davis, Willie Dean, William Deason, John Deffner, Donald DeMatthaeis, S. Denney, Nancy Dennis, Canon Walter Dewart, Leslie Dick, Cornelius Dillenberger Dillon, David Directors, Board of, Fund for Theological Education Dirks, J. Edward District Director, United States Department of Justice Doan, Gilbert E. Doerksen, D.W. Doherty, Dennis Donlan, Thomas Donnelley, Gaylord Donnelly, Strachen Douglass, Truman Drake, George Draper, William Draves, William Driver, James R. Drown, Marilyn Drummond, Richard Duchesne-Guillemin, Jacques Duffy, Dorothy Dunham, Allison Dunne, John S. (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - E, Eagle, Vernon Eaton, Cyrus Eckman, Ernst Edathiparambil, Mathew Edwards, O.C. Eggleston, Herbert Eisenbeis, Walter Ekola, Giles Elkhart Lake, Superintendent of Schools Eklund, Emmet Eliade, Mircea Eller, John C. Ellwood, Robert Elmer, Franklin Elson, Gerhard Elwood, Robert Emerson, James Emory University English, John C. Erfurth, Herb Evans, Donald Evelan, R. Ray Exman, Eugene (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - F-Fa, Faculty Members Faillettaz, Vernon Fairbank, Dexter Falconer, Haven Fallon, Joseph Farmer, Roberta Farmer, George S. Farmer, James A. Farrell, Walter Fate, Russell L. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Fe-Fu, Feldstein, Grace Ferm, Robert Field Chairman Finn, James First National City Bank First Presbyterian Church Fish, John Hall Fisher, Clyde P. Fitchen, Allen Fitzgerald, John D. Fitzpatrick, T. Mallory Flack, Margaret Flander, Robert Fleming, John R. Flender, Herman Flowers, Ronald Fodge, Myron Forbush, Bliss Forstman, H. Jackson Foy, Fred Franklin, John Hope Frein, George H. Frerichs, Ernest Frese, Jerry Frick, May Friede, George Friesen, J.P. Fuente, Ovidio Fuerst, Adrian Fuerst, Wesley Fussler, Herman Future Planning Committee (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - G, Gale, Mary Hardman Gammie, John Garber, Sheldon Gardiner, Margaret Gebauer, Victor Gerard, Francois Germ, Mary Gerrish, Brian Gerry, John R. Geuther, Russell Giacoma, Sister Gibson, Boyd Gilkey, Langdon Glick, G. Wayne Glueck, Nelson Godfrey, Edward Goen, C.C. Goerss, William Golb, Norman Gooding, Charles Goodman, Howard Goodman, Gerald Gordh, George Goulet, Charles Gowe, John E. Grace, J. Peter Grad, Irene Grage, Duang Graham, George Granich, Richard Grant, Robert M. Graubart, Judah Greenberg, David Greene, Shirley Greene, Wayne Grose, George Benedict Grow, Lawrence Gruman, Lawrence Gualtieri, Antonio Gunberg, Edwin Gustafson, James Gustaw, Romuald Guthridge, Frank (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - H, Hass, Harold Hagen, Kenneth Hall, J. Parker Hambrick, Charles Handy, Robert Hanisch, Arthur Hanson, C. Arnold Hardy, Henry Harkins, George Harlow, S. Ralph Haring, Bernard Haroutunian, Helen Haroutunian, Joseph Haroutunian, L. M. Harrelson, Walter Harris, Anita Harris, Jack Harris, Stanley Hart, James Harvard University Press Harvey, Van A. Haskell, Ellery Hastings, Wendi Hayes, Samuel Hedberg, Victor Hefner, Philip Heiges, Donald Heil, Henry Henry, Mary Henry, Edward Henschel, Royal Herman, Stewart Hetzler, Donald Hewitt, Charles Hezelwood, Ruth Hick, John Hill, Harold Hill, William F. Hirsch, Richard Hobgood, Clarence Hodgson, Marshall Hoffman, Clifton Holditch, Kenneth Homas, Peter Hopper, Stanley Horn, Henry Hotchkin, John F. Houle, Cyril Howe, Reuel Hoyt, Robert Hubbard, David Allan Hudson, Winthrop Hunter, David Hughes, John Jay (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - I-J, Ikado, Fujio Immigration and Naturalization Inariyama, Sukeo Jackson, Gordon Jackson, Larry Jacobsen, George Janowitz, Morris Jansen, Hugh M. Jefferson, Frederick Jeffery, M. Pauline Jeffery, P. Jenkins, Daniel Jensen, Theodore John, Mathew Johnson, D. Gale Johnson, Gerald K. Johnson, Harlan Johnson, Lawrence C. Johnson, R. Lewis Johnson, W. Ray Johnson, Vance Johnston, Leslie Jordon, Maureen Jorgenson, Wallace (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - K, Kallas, James Kalven, Harry Kang, Wi Jo Karff, Samuel Karsten, Robert Kasai, Jiuji Kastner, H. Keister, John D. Kegley, Charles Kelly, Frances Kemal, Araikan Kendrick, John H. Kern, Richard Kidd, Samuel Kiel Kimball, Robert Kimpton, Lawrence King, Beth King, Noel Kirchenmann Kitagawa, Joseph Klett, Guy S. Kluger, Richard Knecht, John Knoespel, Kenneth Knopf, Edward Knutson, Kent S. Kohl, Margaret Kort, Wesley Koyama, Kosuke Kraft, Virgil Kramer, Paul Krauss, Paul Kreider, Robert Kretzmann, Edwin Krevitz, Sadelle Kritzeck, James Krodel, Gerhard Kruglick, Lewis John Kucheman, Clark Kudan, Harold Kudo, Sumiko Kurland, Philip (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - L, Labby, Dorreen Lacy, Victor L. LaDue, William Langford, Vernon Langkjaer, Erik Laubach, Eugene Lawson, E. Thomas Lazaroff, Betty Lazure, Noel Leavenworth, Lynn Lee, Amy Lee, Robert E. A. Leen, Walter, V. Lefebre, Hans Lefebre, Waltraud LeFevre, Perry Lehmann, Helmut Lehr, Midred Leifer, Daniel Leisher, Quentin Leonard, Paul Letts, Harold Levi, Edward (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Levner-Lyons, Levner, Nancy Lewis, Douglass Lewis, Frances Lewis, Jack Lewis, Kevin Lieberman, Archie Lincoln, C. Eric Lincicome, Arthur Lindquist, Emory Linkugel, Wil Litchfield, Ann Littell, Franklin Leonetti, David Loewe, Adolph Loewenfeld, Claire Logan, Howard Lokken, James A. Loomer, Bernard Lonergan, Bernard Long, Charles Loos, A. William Lovejoy, James Lowe, Adolph Lowe, Ralph Lubbers, Thomas Luce, Henry Luman, Richard Lund, L. Dale Lund, Gordon C. Lundeen, Malvin Lynn, Robert Lyons, John (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Mac-Mead, MacCorquodale, D. W. MacCormick, Chalmers Mahdi, Muhsin Machle, Edward Makuen, Donald Manfred, Carl Mangin, Frank Manthei, Edward Marks, Rachel Marsh, John Marshall, Robert J. Marshall, Whitfield Martin, LeRoy Martin, Mimi Marty, Martin Marvin, Donn Marx, Lucy Ann Mather, P. Boyd De Matthaeis, S. Matthysse, Steven Mauney, J. Luther Maura, Sister Maxant, William Mays, Benjamin McCaffrey, W. J. McCarney, Howard McConnell, Judson McCord, James I. McCracken, Robert McEldowney, James McDaniel, Michael McDonnell, Kilian McNeill, John T. Meacham, Paul Mead, Sidney (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Mead, Sidney Meechan, John Meland, Bernard Merchant, Moelwyn Mermin, Samuel Merschel, Carl Metropoulos, Nicholas Meuser, Fred W. Meyer, George Meyer, John Michaelson, Robert Michel, Walter Miguens, Emmanuel Mihalik, I. Militzer, William Miller, Dale Miller, Harold Miller, J. H. Miller, Michael Miller, Samuel Million, Elmer Miller, Harold Miller, Patrick Minor, William Minz, Nirmal Miyamoto, Shoson Moltmann, Juergen Moehring, H. R. Mondale, Walter Moreau, Jules Morris, W. S. Morton, James P. Moy, Richard H. Mueller, E. W. Muktarian, Herbert Mueller, William Murphy, Katie Murphy, Robert Murray, Herbert Musser, John (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - N, Nakamura, Kyoko Naples, Jo-Anne Nasr, Seyyed Hossein Nef, John Nelson, James D. Nelson, Warren Nelson, Philip Neusner, Jacob Newton, Lyman Neuhaus, Richard Neville, Robert Newman, Ralph Nichols, Terry Nickle, Keith Nielsen, Erik Nielsen, Niels Norgren, William Nouwen, Henri Nuveen, John O'Brien, John O'Connell, Charles O'Flaherty, James Ogden, Schubert Okamura, Mihoko Ollander, Joel Olmstead, Ronald Olsen, Leonard O'Malley, Steven O'Meara, Marcian Onheiber, Jerome Ong, Walter Onheiber Oppenheimer, Paul Opie, John Ormond, Wilbur O'shaughnessy, Ignatius Ossman, Albert Ossorio, Alfonso Overbeck, James Overman, Conleth Owen, Jane Owen, Kenneth Dale (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - P, Pannenberg, Wolfhardt Panoch, James Parsons, E. Spencer Patrick, Theodore Hall Pauck, Wilhelm Pauck, Marion Paul, Robert S. Paulie, David Paull, Laura Pawlikowski, John Payne, Clarence Pearcy, Henri Pearson, Keith Pease, Kenneth Pelikan, Jaroslav Pelikan, Ralph Pelikan, Maria Penner, Hans Pepper, Curtis Percy, Charles Permissions Editor, University of Chicago Press Perrin, Norman Perry, James A. Peterson, Peter G. Peterson, Ralph Petrea, Raymond Petrovich, Michael Petry, Ray Phayer, Fintan Phelps, T. Torrance Phillips, John Philipson, Morris Pickering, George Pincus, Lilli Pinnington, John E. Pitcher, Al Pixley, George V. Plampin, Jeoffrey Plotkin, Frederick Polish, David Polk, William Presler, Henry Pullapilly, Cyriac Pusey, Nathan (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Q-Ric, Quazzaz, Linda Quinlan, Sterling Rago, Henry Rait, Jill Raun, James J. Ravitch, Norman Rehn, Alexander Regan, Richard J. Regensberg, C. David Reilly, William Reinartz, F. Eppling Reisch, Paul C. Reist, Benjamin A. Reisz, H. Frederick Reitz, Rudiger Reumann, John Reynolds, Frank Rinne, Carl H. Rhoads, Walter F. Ricoeur, Paul (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Rif-Ryl, Rife, J. Merle Robb, J. Wesley Robbins, Wallace Roberts, Howard Roberts, Preston Ricoeur, Paul Riss, Paul Robillard, James Rockefeller, David Roe, Yale Rogers, Robert Rolander, O. R. Rooks, Shelby Rose, Stephen C. Rosen, A. Abbot Roseman, Kenneth D. Rosenthal, Thomas Roth, Robert Rothblatt, Ben Rude, Leslie Ruggles, Wilbur Ruhmkorff, David Rust, John Ryan, William Granger Rylaarsdam, Coert (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Sa-Sch, Saarinen Show, Aline St. Clair, James Sales, Richard Samuels, Richard-Recommendation Sandeen, Ernest Sasnett, J. Randolf Schabel, Gertrude Schaefer, James P. Scharlemann, Robert Scharper, Philip Schattschneider, David A. Scherer, John J. Scheu, Anne Schillebeeckx, Edward Schlitzer, Albert Schmitt, W.W. Schneider, Herbert Schnell, Robert Schossberger, Emily Schott, Franklin H. Schott, Franklin Schroeder, Widick Schuit, William Seeberger, Hans-Jurgen Scherer, James Schulz, Delbert Schutz, Klaus Schwantes, Charles Schloerb, Robert G. (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Sco-Schel, Scott, Nathan Scott, Roland Seay, Thomas Seckel, Margaret Seeberger, Hans-Jurgen Seeberger, Erhard Segerhammer, Carl W. Selby, Miriam Selsor, Wayne Semrow, Joseph Sessions, Robert Paul Sharpe, D.R. Shaw, Robert C. Shaw, Talbert O.-Recommendation Sheboygan ASCS County Office Sheldon, James M. Shelly, Harold P. (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Shen-Slo, Shen, Philip Students, Dean of, Lakeland College Shepard, Massey H. Sherman, Dallas Sherman, Franklin Sherrell, Richard Shinohara, Koichi Shuster, George Siebeck, Hans Georg Siebeck, Paul Siegel, Martin Simpson, Alan Sinclair, Lawrence Singleton, Charles S. Siskin, Edgar Sisler, George F. Sittler, Joseph Skarsten, Trygve Sloan, David M. (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Sm-So, Smith, Clyde Curry Smith, Donald B. Smith, Elwyn A. Smith, John Abernathy Smith, Huston Smith, B. Julian Smith, W.A.S. Smith, Timothy L. Smucker, Donovan E. Smylie, James H. Solomon, P. Soule, Carl Soneson, J. Melburn Sonnedecker, Glenn Sorenson, C.W. Souri, J.D. (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Spi-Ste, Spiegler, Gerhardt Spinka, Matthew Staack, Hagen Staehelin, Ernst Stammler, Heinrich Stapleton, George T. Stark, Ronald Stassen, Glen Stauffer, John N. Steece, Arvel Stein, Leonard Stendahl, Krister Stephanou, Eusebuus Steurer, Lorraine Stevens, George (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Sti-Swi, Stinnette, Charles Stokes, Mack B. Stolp, Richard L. Stoner, Elizabeth Strandness, Harold Streeter, Robert Strodtz, Margaret Stroud, Virgil Stucki, Margaret Suelflow, August Suenens, Leon-Joseph Sullivan, Joseph Sullivan, Kathryn Superintendent of Schools, Plymouth, Wisconsin Superintendent of Schools, Chicago, Illinois Sutherland, Rand Sutherland, Malcolm Swanson, Reuben Switz, Theodore (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - T, Tait, L. Gordon Tavard, George H. Telford, George TenZythoff, Gerrit Teske, Mike Theisen, Stephen Thiel, Harry C. Thomas, Carl E. Thomasma, David Thomas, Russell Thomapson, Manley Thompson, Robert Thorkelson, W.L. Thornton, Catherine Tillich, Hannah Tobias, Robert Toomey, H.L. Towne, Edgar Tracy, David Trinterud, Leonard J. Trotter, F. Thomas Turkington, Edward Turle, Tod United States Department of Justice, Immigration and Naturalization Service Twardy, Stan Unwin, Stanley Urdang, Laurence Vajta, Vilmos Van Ackeren, Gerald VanBoskird, J.J. Vanderhaar, Gerard Van Dusen, Henry Pitney Verhalen, Philip A. Verhulst, Toger Vos, Nelvin L. Voobus, A. Vunderink, Ralph William (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Wa-Wel, Waddams, Canon Herbert Waggoner, Mary Wagner, Donald Wagner, Walter Wallace, Martha Wallace, William Walline, Edward Walsh, Chad Walters, John Ward, Montgomery Ward, Harold C. Wardell, Beatrice Watkins, George H. Way, William Weaver Webber, G.W. Weber, Lon W. Weeks, Ian G. Weidman, Gilbert L. Weihe, Clifton M. Weiland, Paula Weintraub, Helen Weisbaker, Dimis Welch, Claude Wells, Edward K. Wells, Ronald V. (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Wen-Wil, Wentz, Richard E. Welch, Claude Werblowsky, R.J. Zwi Wentz, Richard E. Werner, M.L. Western Clergy Bureau Westlund, Virgil Whalen, John P. Whitley, Oliver Whittaker, Frederick W. Wick, Ruth C. Wienhorst, Sue Wikander, Stig Wikgren, Allen Wilcoxen, Jay Wilder, Amos Wilder, Phelps Wilken, Robert L. Williams, Colin Williams, Daniel Williams, George H. Wilson, E.C. Wilson, John T. (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Win-Zie, Winter, Gibson Winters, Janet Lewis Witt, Charles E. Wolbrecht, Walter Wolf, C. Umhau Wood, John Woodring, Mary E. World Council of Churches World Division of the Board of Missions Worthy, James C. Wright, C. Conrad Wright, G. Ernest Yonan, Edward Young, Canon Edwyn Young, Robert Yu, Anthony Zahn, D. Willard Zeidler, C.H. Ziegler, Jesse (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 8: Sidney Mead Correspondence
    - Mead to Brauer, 1969 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Mead to Brauer, 1970-1979 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Brauer to Mead, 1970-1979 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Mead Festschrift Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Mead to Martin Marty, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Brauer to Mead, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Brauer to Mead, 1982-1987 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Mead to Brauer, 1982-1984 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Brauer to Mead, 1988-1989 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Mead to Brauer, 1985-1989 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Mead Comments, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Brauer Notes on Mead, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Mead to Brauer, 1983-1996 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Mead Comments, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Mead to Brauer, 1990-1994 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Brauer to Mead, 1990-1998 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Mead to Marty, 1994 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Mead to Brauer, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Brauer, Notes on Mead, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Mead Lecture, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 8)
- Series III: Federated Theological Faculty. 1943-1960
  Series III, Federated Theological Faculties, consists of alphabetical subject files relating to Brauer's involvement with the Federated Theological Faculties. The formation of the FTF in 1943, formalized the relationships between the Divinity School at the University of Chicago, Disciples Divinity House, Meadville Theological School and the Chicago Theological Seminary. Brauer served as the first and only dean of FTF from 1955 until the federation was dissolved in 1960. Materials in the Series include administrative reports, minutes and correspondence, items related to the creation of the B.D. degree. The series also includes information about the defederation of FTF, organizations Brauer was involved with, and a significant amount of material relating to the conference "Religion Faces the Atomic Age," held in 1958.
  - American Association of Theological Schools (AATS), information bulletin and minutes, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - AATS General Information, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - AATS Constitution, Incorporation, Dues, Audit, 1956-1958 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - AATS Report, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - AATS, Minutes, information bulletins, correspondence, 1957 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - AATS, Minutes, information bulletins, correspondence, 1958 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Accounts for FY 1957-1958, Equipment and Expenses (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Accounts for FY 1957-1958, Research (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Accounts for FY 1957-1958, Travel (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Account Book, Dean's Equipment and Expenses, 1956-1957 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Accounts for FY 1957-1958, Various (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Accounts, 1958-1960 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Admissions Requirements, 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Advertising, National Council Outlook, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - A.M./PhD. Committee Report to Faculty, 1957 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - American Association of Seminary Professors of Christian Ethics, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - American Christian Palestine Association, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - American Unitarian Association, 1956-1957 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Baptist Theological Union, 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Baptist Theological Union, 1940-1957 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - B.D. Program (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - B.D. Committee Report Intro, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - B.D. Degree Program, 1957-1958 (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - B.D. Degree Program, Notes on Prep, n. d. (Box 21, Folder 14)